We've all spent vacations in Italy,
Venice,
Rome,
the beaches,
the churches,
the food.
Okay,
okay,
it's a bit of a cliche to say,
but across the Alps from France,
it's still a magical place.
I've been going there for 30 years,
ever since I met a group of Italians at a vacation club.
Back in those days,
we wore our sunglasses in our hair.
We added O's and A's to every word to make ourselves understood until I decided to really learn Italian.
I studied history in Verona.
I worked as a bartender on Lake Garda.
And finally,
I worked as a sports journalist.
I fell in love with the country across the Alps.
But nowadays,
I barely recognize the Italy that I love so much.
He has hypnotized,
captivated,
and enchanted them.
The Italians have chosen their new leader,
Matteo Salvini.
He was elected on March 7,
2018,
thanks to a coalition with the Five Star Movement.
Salvini has Italy at his feet.
Matteo
Despite the fact that there are two people who share the role of Prime Minister,
Luigi Di Meo is no longer part of the official picture.
In barely one year,
Salvini's party,
known as the League,
went from 17%
to 30%
of votes.
in the last regional elections,
Salvini is advancing as fast as a Ferrari.
Salvini's nickname is Il Capitano,
the captain.
His method is to speak with no filter.
of nothing and no one.
With this young
40-something from Milan,
you can forget about the polite forms of address used by the political pros.
Matteo shoots from the hip.
His preferred themes are migrants,
the Italian political left,
Europe,
Merkel and even Macron.
Everyone gets raked across the coals.
Populist,
racist and even fascist.
That's how this friend of Marine Le Pen is depicted outside of Italy.
In his own country,
his detractor
have trouble making themselves heard over the 78%
of Italians who support his policy on immigration.
Up until now,
I'd always understood the people who had been my friends for 30 years.
There were sensitive topics like Mussolini,
immigration,
Senadine Sedan's headbutt,
but when it comes to Salvini,
I find it hard to understand.
I'd rather be the Minister of the Interior and send some clandestines to their homes.
This is better for me.
So I rented a car and went to meet some of these Italians,
so they could tell me why they voted for Salvini.
We stopped to speak with an entrepreneur in Verona.
A traditional Catholic.
And then a lawyer in the La Marche region.
A young student in Bologna and a metalworker.
A senator who's close to Salvini.
And finally,
olive oil producers in the Naples region.
1250 miles from north to south in Matteo Salvini's Italy,
the brat who makes Europe shake in its boots.
Adoptive city,
Verona,
the capital of the Veneto region.
It has all the scenes right out of a postcard.
Old stones,
medieval statues,
and elegant women in furs.
Verona is rich,
very rich.
An opulent region with 6%
unemployment.
It is rich with marble quarries,
delicious wines,
and thousands of small to medium businesses and industries which have made the Italian system successful.
First stop,
Busolengo,
to see my old friend Luca Perabolo.
He was not very enthusiastic at the idea of talking about politics.
Luca is 42.
He's the head sales representative for a small cosmetics company.
Your colleagues from the TV also use it.
Yes?
Yes,
because it's opaque,
against the lights.
Oh,
really?
Yes,
it's true,
it's true.
There are about ten employees,
including Luca's wife,
his brother-in-law,
and his next-door neighbor.
We start the interview.
So they moved to the left.
Years of hell for Italy,
for the south,
in general,
for the north,
etc.
So let's all move to the right,
Berlusconi in the sense of the center-right,
even the right in quotation marks.
extreme,
finite,
to the times and even there they come out and above all there is Bossi,
the old Bossi,
do you remember him?
I have it hard.
We have it hard Roma thief and then he stole more than
than those in Rome.
So,
who do you vote for?
Who remains?
I mean,
there's very few left.
So you vote,
in my opinion,
or at least I did,
you vote for those who seem to have the least bad ideas.
And you,
what did you vote for before?
So,
I did several years in which I didn't vote for anything,
I cancelled the ballot.
I made a big X on the whole board.
Luca is a bit cynical,
and yet on March 7th,
2018,
he casts his ballot for Salvini.
I tell you the truth,
not because I share my ideas or the political program of these,
but to give a little attempt,
a kick,
an attempt to see if these,
once I find one that does what he says.
It was one of Salvini's campaign promises,
a flat tax,
a single rate income tax for individuals,
but also for businesses,
a rate that could be capped at 25%
of revenue.
Some people feel it would benefit the wealthy.
Guys,
it works like this everywhere.
If we make money,
we make them run abroad.
If we make companies run abroad,
if we punish those who have a nice shop,
those who have a nice jacket,
those who have a nice car,
these go abroad,
buy abroad,
spend abroad,
and then they work abroad.
This is what convinced Luca and Stefano,
who hoped that this policy would come into effect very quickly.
With Salvini,
it's about politics à la carte.
Tailor-made,
pleasing everyone.
even some of the most conservative voters,
building from another time in a neighborhood in Verona.
We are traditional Catholic,
so we are the ex-Orandi and the ex-Credendi.
I'll say it in Latin so everyone can understand.
Matteo Castagnà created Christus Rex,
an association with roughly 50 members,
including his wife and some friends.
Their fight is against abortion and all those who support the practice which they consider immoral.
It's a very normal practice,
if you decide not to have a child,
you throw it away,
because it's not a life,
because for them,
the modern world,
they decided that life happens with birth,
now it's not even that,
instead for us,
Catholics,
traditionalists,
it happens when there is conception,
and that's where life is born.
Matteo and his wife brought their fight against abortion to the streets of Verona.
They organized protests.
A few months ago,
faced with these religious zealots,
Verona's city council gave in.
of the communals of the particular way of the league of a motion that asks the municipality of who asked the municipality of verona to name verona city of life and to support associations
two in particular with economic contributions which work to to discourage women from aborting.
A victory that led Matteo Castagnà all the way to the Chamber of Deputies last January because Matteo and his friends from Christus found support in Salvini's government,
notably in the person of Lorenzo Fontana,
Minister for Family.
and against abortion,
obviously.
And so,
for us,
it was a...
I don't say a miracle,
but having a family minister pro-family,
because until now there has never been one,
is a satisfaction.
The mark...
He is giving to the
Ministry and it seems that from a cultural point of view,
he is breathing a different air in Italy.
For those who believe that the good God gives us a hand,
the family is founded on the union of a man.
I thank His Holiness Pope Francis for repeating what is right.
At least it's clear.
I dare to ask one last question before leaving our friends from Christus Rex.
Do you have daughters?
No.
And you,
ma'am?
That's why we feel more and more and believe even more in the spark of life.
Birth rates are a big problem in Italy.
With only 1.3 babies for each woman,
the country has aged a lot.
Salvini promises to give it a nice facelift.
To get his message across,
Salvini speaks directly to his voters on social media.
Berlusconi had television.
With Salvini,
it's Facebook.
With nearly 3.5 million fans,
Il Capitano is the most followed European politician on Facebook.
He posts between five and six times a day.
And like a good friend,
Matteo puts everything on display.
His passion for cats?
For AC Milan,
for campaign speeches,
the best of his TV appearances,
what he eats,
and some montages that he knows the secret to.
Matteo's a real geek.
We're back on the road heading south towards the Adriatic coast and the region of La Marche,
to Senegalia,
a seaside resort between Rimini and Riccione.
It's like a scene from a Fellini film.
In summer,
you have to fight to put your towel down on its beaches.
Today,
we hardly run into anyone except retirees.
The young people are elsewhere.
When you are caught,
in both wrists,
to free yourself,
you open,
like a shoe in your belly,
then the left arm takes this arm and you turn.
Here there is also a lever.
He turns with me until I decide to turn him again and there is another lever,
this time on the wrist,
and then I find it here.
This is the owner of the Jiu-Jitsu Club,
Roberto Paradisi,
a well-known lawyer in the region.
A few months ago,
Roberto had an idea to come to the aid of all those in Italy who had been victims of violence and wanted to learn how to defend themselves.
He created his association with a network of martial arts clubs throughout Italy.
This is a Senegal-Perugia project.
In Lombardy,
there are various Lombardy gyms.
There are also in Milan,
Rolambro,
Pavia,
Arese.
A girl joined Milan,
just recently,
a girl who told us she had been robbed twice,
once on the train,
and she was very scared,
a young girl,
a girl...
We have a 26-27 year old girl here.
She asked us to protect her.
The most difficult thing for me is to find a way to recover.
I want girls to know that it is possible to get their heads up again after such a tragedy.
Fighting for what is known as legitimate defense has been Paradisi's obsession ever since he defended a young Italian who was attacked in his home by his fiancé's ex-boyfriend.
...and was investigated.
But our order states that the criminal action is mandatory...
...and that it is a legitimate defense.
It is not a right,
and from here I was saying that it must be a right again...
...but it is a discriminatory case,
that is,
it is a case of non-punishability.
So if it is a state concession and it is not a right...
...I will investigate you.
The public prosecutor had to investigate him.
And for over a year this boy was under investigation.
But since March 28th,
2019,
that is no longer the case.
Salvini is proud as a peacock because he got his law passed,
as he promised during his campaign.
From now on,
under legitimate defense,
anyone who is attacked at home and defends themselves will no longer be prosecuted.
I don't want Italians to go around armed with guns and if someone messes up the parking lot or the parking lot in the second row,
you make an account regulation with the Kalashnikov.
But I don't even want,
as has happened too many times,
that if a criminal,
a robber,
a rapist,
enters masked and armed in the house,
in the store of someone,
I cannot defend myself before I have understood how bad this guy wants to make me.
I think that in the house of Italians,
legitimate defense is a right.
It's a right.
For everyone.
But defend oneself against whom?
Crime rates are going down all across Italy,
which Paradisi disputes.
There is a slight decline in crime,
because there is a slight decline in denunciations.
The slight decline in denunciations should not be confused...
With the decline of crime.
Look,
in the last four months,
here,
in this studio,
in the Androne below,
last thing done yesterday afternoon,
they stole two bicycles from us.
One of my racing bicycles,
a bicycle that I was going to ride on Sunday to do my errands,
and a bicycle of a colleague of mine.
They get in the Androne,
follow the chains and take the bicycles away.
A Siberia-like landscape three hours from the Adriatic coast.
Immaculate plains as far as the eye can see.
Emilia-Romagna,
the historic stronghold of the Italian left.
This morning people are chatting in the town of Senegata,
Bolognese.
Is there a problem?
No,
no,
listen to him.
He's
French. Yes,
he's French.
Macron,
resignation Macron,
resignation Great It's not the best taste,
but people here like to make fun of the situation in France.
And there's another person who shares this opinion,
the mayor.
Giuseppe Vincinelli.
He had us visit the little
18th century theatre which adjoins his office.
And above all,
he remembers the day when he took over Senegata's City Hall from the left.
Yes,
because here the left has always ruled,
since 70 years,
since the post-war period,
the left.
And in 2014,
despite the fact that in 2014 the left went very well in the European elections,
I managed to win in this community.
Okay,
with a coalition of the center-right.
there was Forza Italia.
Forza Italia,
Lega.
There are moments when you need to give a turn.
Saint-Agata is a war trophy for the League,
to have taken a city hall in the heart of socialist country.
Giuseppe will never be able to thank Matteo enough.
However,
he's not crazy about the French,
and I got a scolding.
Macron is giving us terrorists who have killed people in France and they have to pay for their crimes and they don't give us any money.
He's doing this,
which is,
beyond all,
a form of justice against the victims.
Salvini succeeded where his predecessors had failed.
He got Cesar Battisti returned to Italy,
a former member of the armed proletarians for communism.
He was convicted in absentia for the murder of four people.
and was welcomed at the airport in Rome last January
14th by Salvini,
who was wearing a police jacket.
Obviously,
it was broadcast live on Facebook.
Italy,
the United States,
fortunately,
where those who make mistakes pay for the certainty of the penalty,
the terrorists are no longer impunished.
Salvini rejoiced.
Italy's policeman-in-chief had succeeded in handcuffing this man who,
after fleeing France,
had taken refuge in Brazil.
Until Brazil's new president,
Bolsonaro,
turned him over to his friend Salvini.
But other former members of the Red Brigades are still taking refuge in France.
of the assassins can enjoy immunity in a state close to ours,
in the European community.
But it's unthinkable.
The assassins must go to jail.
However,
it's a historic stronghold of the Italian left.
One of the longest standing representatives is waiting for us in this parking lot.
When he was killed by the party,
for four or five years,
I didn't vote anymore.
Maurizio,
a leftist ex-union member,
fought his political battles at the Fondori de Montessoro,
a factory that subcontracts for the automobile industry.
It's not something out of Dickens,
but the work is hard and repetitive.
At 62,
Maurizio expected a well-deserved retirement,
but according to him,
his party betrayed him.
The left in Italy voted that people retire at 67 years old,
without a way out.
And you,
what age do you want?
Now,
with the reform,
there is a small chance,
it's called quota 100,
of going out at 62 years old.
I'm 62 years old,
I worked 31 years in the foundry,
31 years,
not a day,
31 years.
So I know what it means,
my skin bears the signs of the foundry,
maybe even my lungs.
Once again,
Salvini heard the anger of the Maurizios of Italy and drastically cut the Frenero law,
the retirement reform law named after the former Minister of Labour under Matteo Renzi.
With the quota 100,
which takes into account the arduousness of the job,
100,000 Italians have retired since January.
I'm 63 years old,
I'm an airport employee.
Finally,
I have 42 years of hard work.
Thanks to Quota 100,
I can go to retirement.
I would like to thank everyone who participated until this happened.
Thank you again.
According to predictions,
Quota 100 will cost Italy 33 billion euros,
where Salvini is going to find the money is a mystery.
We want to go out at an age when it is possible.
Having a decent life,
decent,
enjoying retirement.
42 years of retirement,
I think,
are enough to guarantee a life for 4 or 5 years with the family.
He's going to be a grandfather now,
I have two grandchildren too.
Congratulations I voted for Salvini because I went to Bologna to hear him.
When he came to Bologna,
he said,
these are my points,
and I read them.
I will try to make them happen.
Your pension?
Pension.
Salary?
Salary.
Lower taxes.
It's not...
I'll explain.
Lowering taxes is important for someone who pays a lot of taxes,
but it's important for us.
I pay 27%
of taxes.
My wife,
who works at the post office in December with the 13th,
has paid 38%
of taxes.
She can't afford to pay taxes anymore.
We don't have...
The possibility of our salary to do something.
While in the 90s and until 2000,
you had a part of the salary that remained,
you could put it away,
in fact you went to the bank and had the money.
So with Quota 100,
Salvini won the hearts of retirees.
But he also found ways to win the hearts of young Italians.
We're back in the center of Bologna.
We're going to the
Box 66 in Casalecchio di Reno to talk about Industry 4.0 and Startup.
Perspectives that have been created thanks to the last financial maneuver.
We'll be waiting for you in a moment.
So you think he'd been doing this all his life.
At only 20 years old,
Niccolò Malossi runs the Lega Geo...
Giovanni,
the youth branch of the League in Emilia-Romagna.
And when you're 20,
you campaign on
Instagram.
follow us in a physical way,
but they follow us virtually.
Off camera,
Nicolò is a brilliant engineering student and a young man like any other,
always ready to joke around,
except when you hand him a microphone.
If you laugh,
it's not good.
Get out.
So this is the situation in Italy.
The most young people are our electoral program.
Perfect.
Okay,
maybe I didn't publish this.
Thank you.
Before answering my question about Salvini,
The question of right or left,
up or down,
there is a part called good sense and on the other hand the more unbridled globalism.
All the coffees?
Four coffees?
Three coffees and one deca?
But in Bologna the red,
Salvini isn't universally liked.
In Bologna,
Salvini is worrisome because under the archways of this magnificent city,
the league is gobbling up terrain,
one voter at a time,
thanks to little soldiers like Niccolo.
His devotion to the league started four years ago when he was a kid.
he ran into Matteo Salvini by chance on vacation at the seaside.
A simple conversation he had,
dressed in shorts,
became a political commitment.
Appointed head of the Youth League,
he learned the business and had to relate to the media.
I'm disheartened.
Ah yes,
you've got to learn the hard way.
However,
in terms of organization,
there's nothing to add.
Are there only men?
No,
no,
the girls are coming.
Ah yes,
in Salvini's league,
women have trouble making a place for themselves.
This evening,
Nicolò and his friend Umberto have organized a little conference in the stadium.
the suburbs of Bologna,
about an industry 4.0 concept,
smart cities.
About 50 participants,
some very young and others not so young,
have come to listen to people who work in start-ups talk about their experience.
I have three other boys,
Virality.
Virality is a start-up that produces artificial intelligence algorithms for the optimization of content and for the construction of advertising campaigns.
As usual,
Niccolo plays his part.
There are two ideas at the bottom.
On the one hand,
we have the left that believes in developing the Italian economy in a simple way.
We import new immigrants,
possibly with little professional skills and hardly integrated.
At 10.30 p.m.,
the conference takes on a feel of a political...
meeting.
The vote is the tool we have,
as long as we have it,
we must defend it.
It is the tool we have to be able to react with respect to how much is happening around us.
That's why I'm making an appeal right now,
because in a short time there will be,
in addition to the administrative and the European,
but I'm already making an appeal because don't waste this weapon,
this chance to make a difference.
20%
of Italians under 25 voted for Salvini.
Today these young people are ready to take political action.
21-year-old Luca,
for example,
is running in May in the Pianoro Municipal Elections as a candidate for the league.
It's a beautiful road,
the Futa,
that must be valued,
so to give value to tourism.
And you must be dressed in a tie or not?
I will,
I will also wear that,
but I'm a bit like Salvini,
with the fur coat and the shirt.
Thank you,
thank you.
The next day,
still in Bologna,
we meet up with Umberto Lamorgia.
He's the one who organized yesterday's chat,
and he's rather content with it.
Umberto is a smart guy.
He has a master's degree.
He studied marketing in France and England,
but he learned politics from the league.
The space and the possibility to do something concrete,
even at a political level,
with my ideas,
which were already those.
So I already had this kind of background,
this idea.
I also did the political training school of the League,
I had followed in Milan.
What is this?
It is a training school organized by the League,
by the League at the national level,
which every time...
At least one student per year organizes courses.
I,
for example,
was involved in a six-month weekend.
So it's not a very intense commitment.
The league's political training school is Matteo Salvini's creation.
The debate is about training.
The school,
which was launched five years ago,
trains and educates the League's advocates to be its political boots on the ground.
The League's school is the place to be.
Speakers from all backgrounds vie to be there.
People like Berlusconi,
economists,
parliamentarians,
and even star journalists from RAI Broadcasting,
like Bruno...
Uno Vespa,
who presents the biggest political show on the public network.
It's a curious mix.
In this course,
in this training school,
we deal with macro themes every time.
For example,
for the first time,
we deal with the history of Italy.
But the history of Italy,
the aspects of...
come here a book crucial a critic she could she sono static on a process of unification a common I'll Italia sent a quest of orter regionalism a quest o'chiamo rechiamo a la autonomia a tifa capire
the historical reasons of Italy,
which had a very strong and late unity.
The normal school where we all go teaches only by simplifying that the unity of Italy is the good of the world,
or that European federalism would be the great perfection,
etc.
This is the whole school of the left.
Its history filtered through the idea of the league.
At the end of training,
participants receive a certificate,
which is indispensable if they want to join the party.
And of course,
their selfie with il Capitano.
Behind Salvini the showman,
there is a strategic thinker,
who plays the provocateur,
but weaves his web behind the scenes.
His masterstroke was winning over the southern Italy,
the Mesegiorno.
The area of Italy...
that he ridiculed when he was just a deputy,
and the league was known as the Northern League.
Salvini,
the separatist,
dreamed of splitting Italy in two,
to create Padania,
an autonomous province around the golden triangle of Milan,
Turin,
and Verona.
Roma la drona,
Rome the thief,
he chanted against the capital at the time.
He claimed that those in Rome lived high on the hog at the expense of northern cities.
A few years later,
he's changed his tune.
We're headed to Rome,
the capital of Italy and the seat of its political institutions.
There's a soccer game this evening at Stadio Olimpico.
Rome is hosting Matteo Salvini's favorite club,
AC Milan.
Il Capitano leaves no one indifferent here.
The worst thing that could have happened in Italy.
Salvini is the worst thing.
He wasn't always very kind to the people of the South,
though.
No,
not this one.
Absolutely not.
We don't forget him,
since we're from the South.
So,
why is he so popular here in Rome?
I think it's because we're all a little tired,
right?
Of the old political class.
Of the old political class,
so let's say,
okay.
This is what it offers at the moment.
Well,
come on.
We've tried a lot.
Let's try another one.
I don't agree with his policies.
It's a too...
I don't want to say racist,
but we're getting closer to racism.
He says no,
I'm not racist.
it's normal that he says no.
But what he does in reality...
It shows that he is.
Or at least,
unfortunately,
many Italians are following him.
A little because there is this fear.
Because he created fear in the face of the blacks,
of the guys who come from outside.
It's a problem,
because clearly it's a problem.
Because now Africa is getting in more and more every day.
But we have to be more human,
more humanitarian and try to help.
these people.
Migrants are the number one issue in Italy.
Matteo Salvini's stock and trade.
He built his electoral base on the fear that is provoked by this ceaseless wave of lifeboats in distress landing by the thousands on Italian shores.
And the city he uses to symbolize this is Lampedusa.
I prefer to be the Minister of the Interior and send some clandestine people back home.
I can do this better.
Salvini gave himself the mission of putting an end to the flow of immigrants once and for all.
He doesn't hesitate to get angry with his European neighbors.
He's a permanent guest on television shows to talk about the subject,
and he proudly proclaims his track record.
I will do this,
these are the numbers of last year.
I will deal with 2017 and 2018.
Thanks to my commitment and the entire government,
we have landed almost 100,000 less landings.
You are privileged,
you are the first to see it,
probably.
Here they are.
The acts of the Catania Tribunal.
Sections.
Ministerial crimes.
You already guessed that there is something that obviously concerns my person and concerns you too.
Tribunal of Catania,
section,
ministerial crimes.
I'm back to being investigated.
Now I'm reading you,
In this particular case,
Salvini was saved by his parliamentary immunity.
How funny.
And to justify his aggressive policies against immigrants,
Mateo can count on support from
from an unexpected ally.
Tony Iwobi,
62 years old,
originally from Nigeria,
made history last year.
He arrived in Italy as a bricklayer.
In 1996,
Tony Iwobi became a member of the League and an active campaigner in the Bergamo region.
The senator has known Salvini for a long time,
so in
2014, Matteo came to Italy.
I have a very good relationship with my troops.
You said immediately yes,
I will do it without any hesitation.
Why am I the only African representative to choose immigration?
Is there a risk or no?
Absolutely,
because I saw it as a call for responsibility.
Because I felt that someone had to make them understand what immigration is.
Look,
the League,
I say it with all my heart,
without any middle ground,
the League,
at least the League of Matteo Salvini,
has never been against immigration as such.
Because we are aware,
he himself told me,
he has always told me,
that no one...
on the face of the earth,
on this planet,
can stop immigration.
Because immigration belongs to man.
Immigration is in the DNA of man.
But it must be regulated.
And it is the task of the policy to regulate it.
What has happened in this country in the last seven years,
in the countries of the left government?
It has nothing to do with the immigration I know or experienced.
I am also fighting for my fellow Continentals who will understand sooner or later.
Because by facilitating uncontrolled immigration,
clandestinity,
it is the greatest idiocy and crime that man can commit.
I know what you're thinking.
Tony is Salvini's decoy to justify his policy on immigration.
Maybe.
In any case,
the senator takes his role very seriously.
to be able to concentrate on the territory to solve these problems,
because they had really created an unacceptable situation.
Even for us Africans,
we were ashamed,
seeing our fellow nationals,
human beings,
who were abandoned,
to their fate,
on the territory.
To end the interview,
we talked about soccer and the hateful messages of certain Italians toward the French team during the World Cup.
For the first time,
an African team has won the World Cup.
But once again,
Tony Iwobi evaded the question.
But there's nothing to laugh about.
True,
Salvini blocked the flow of migrants who were landing in Italy.
But they moved on to Spain.
not to mention those who,
stuck in Libya,
were enslaved.
Far from there,
from now on,
the Italians sleep peacefully.
But the man who dreams of being the only prime minister has another step to take,
no doubt the most difficult,
reconciling with the people of Naples,
with whom he has a bone of contention.
He claims it was a youthful indiscretion,
a different time,
when he was a hot-headed campaigner for the Northern League.
Naples and Salerno region are the Garden of Italy,
with its agricultural plains and its thousands of greenhouses like mirrors.
The region's other bounty is olive oil,
made with the Rotondella variety.
It's less well-known than olive oil from Puglia,
and has a very particular taste.
This is sweeter.
This one is sweeter.
Because those who use it everywhere prefer a less aggressive taste.
I prefer the other one.
Yes,
me too.
The Di Giorgio brothers took over the family business years ago and are grooming their children to take over from them.
However,
the industry is not flourishing.
You used to do this with your hands?
Yes,
once you used to pick up...
Did you do it?
No,
I didn't.
I remember.
Young people don't want to make sacrifices in the countryside.
In the countryside,
they all run away.
Why don't you pay?
Not because I don't pay,
because at work...
It's very stressful.
And so many sacrifices are required.
And then you don't get the work you put in.
Because there is a lot of competition from outside.
For example,
in Italy,
if you want to make a liter of good oil here in our area,
you have to sell it for at least 6-7 euros.
But to get the expenses,
it's not that you earn it.
And then you go to the supermarket and they sell it for 3-4 euros.
It's all imported oil.
And he can't sell it for 6 or 7 euros.
And he can't recover how much he spent.
Faced with the anguish of these Neapolitan producers,
Salvini has perhaps found a solution.
Making a profit is a political act.
Because it is clear that the same milk that is paid 60 cents in Sardinia and in Italy,
in Romania is paid less than half.
30 cents,
so buying Italian means being well and helping Italian workers.
Salvini is doing the battle,
but in Honord it is true,
it was a battle that had already started for a few decades,
in short,
on the protection of national productions.
The point is that we have managed to have the standards that establish the traceability,
the label,
the origin of the raw material.
But there is still a lack of control.
National food preferences interest the Di Giorgio brothers.
Domenico deals with agricultural issues in the region for the league.
He used to vote for Forza Italia and Berlusconi,
but despite Salvini's taunting words,
he won them over with his actions.
I think the battles he is waging are already visible.
On immigration it is evident that...
...that managed to block a migratory flow that invaded Italy every year.
Today it is a reality.
Now,
the method that it is using will be debatable,
but the result has been achieved.
Undoubtedly.
Legitimate defense,
which will now become law,
is another topic that is at the heart of the Italians.
It is unimaginable that one cannot stay at home at ease.
Salvini's doctrine has been learned by heart,
even in southern Italy.
Last February,
during Sardinia's regional elections,
the league's candidate received 48%
of votes.
The five-star movement got only 11%.
All of this in barely a year.
Impressive.
The Salvini phenomenon and his success resonate outside of Italy.
This was last November.
The young man there,
reading from his sheets of paper in halting Italian,
is Jordan Bardella,
who leads the list for the national rally.
He was invited to speak by the youth league,
and Jordan Bardella needed no urging to take the stage,
because nowadays,
for all its populist political parties in Europe,
the league is the example to follow.
Demonstrate che stoppare l'immigrazione è possibile.
Demostrate che riportare la sicurezza in Italia è possibile.
Nelle vostre vie,
nelle vostre campagne e sulle vostre...
One of the goals of Salvini is to have this kind of big coalition in Europe of all the sovereignist parties that are attached to what Salvini calls the revolution of common sense,
those who want to defend the identity of European peoples and those who want to give back trust to the people in the people's place.
The success of
Salvini gives you wings,
gives you hope?
Salvini is the example that it is possible.
It is the example that when you want,
you can.
It is the example that when you want to give the power back to the people,
then it is possible.
And it is the example that if the people want to take power again,
then they can.
Luca,
Matteo Castagna and his wife,
Mr.
Paradisi,
the mayor of Santa Gata,
Niccolò,
Maurizio,
Senator Uobi,
and the DiGiorgio brothers,
they all have a good reason to have voted for and supported Matteo Salvini.
But the prime minister's outrageousness will have consequences.
There's a split within Italian society,
the different sides are becoming more agitated,
and the worst is never far off.
For example,
what happened on March 21st,
2019.
A bus created chaos on a highway in the suburbs of Milan.
These school children you see screaming and running are coming back from hell.
At 11 a.m.,
their bus driver,
Usenio,
an Italian of Senegalese origin,
tied them up along with their teachers,
doused the bus with gas,
and threatened to burn them alive.
The police arrived just in time and saved 51 students before the bus caught fire.
With his crazy act,
the bus driver wanted to protest the deaths of migrants in the Mediterranean.
He holds Salvini responsible,
an accusation which obviously doesn't hold up.
But it's a sign that something is amiss in Salvolini land.